《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break...
失去兄弟仿佛生活中出现一个巨大的空洞
Losing a brother, the massive hole that leaves in your life.
失去丈夫也一样
Like the same massive hole losing a husband makes.
你弟弟死了 林肯
Your brother's dead, Lincoln.
那你要怎么解释这个
How do you explain that?
- 林肯·布鲁斯  - 雅各布
- Lincoln Burrows.  - Jacob.
林肯叔叔
Uncle Lincoln!
911 我家有人持械入室
911. I have an armed intruder in my house.
我们触发了一些事
We've awoken something...
一些被极力掩盖的关于迈克尔的事
Something people are trying to hide about Michael.
我都不知道我们在反击谁
I don't know who we're fighting.
我们去也门查清楚
Let's go to Yemen and find out.
你对也门一无所知
You don't know a damn thing about Yemen.
我会找到有门路的人
I'll find someone who does.
这个国家己支离破碎了 大家都想逃出去
The country's falling apart. Everyone wants out.
欢迎来到内战
Welcome to the civil war.
快来 否则我们都得死
Come quickly, or we'll all be dead!
- 联络人是谁来着  - 一个叫希巴的女人
- Who's that contact again?  - A woman named Sheba.
迈克尔可能被卷入到什么严重的事情里了
Michael's caught in the middle of something big.
卡尼尔·乌提斯是个臭名昭著的恐怖分子
Kaniel Outis is a big-time terrorist.
我们已经安排了一次到奥杰吉亚监狱的探视
We've arranged a visit to Ogygia Prison.
意思是 迈克尔在那里吗
That mean Michael's in there?
迈克尔
Michael?
我的名字不叫迈克尔 我也不知道你们是谁
My name isn't Michael, and I don't know who you are.
狱卒 带我回牢房
迈克你在干什么 该死的
Michael, what are you doing, damn it?!
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
随着ISIL恐怖组织逼近首都
The fighting in Yemen intensified today
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
今天也门的战况也愈演愈烈
as ISIL forces get ever nearer to the capitol.
叛军已经声明其意图是接管国家
The rebels, who have the stated intent of taking over
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻译     春天里的小熊    薇薇安    Alex
建立一个激进的伊斯兰国
the country and establishing a radical caliphate,
并决心要解救其领导人阿布·拉马尔
are also bent on freeing their leader, Abu Ramal,
翻译     宜九零   高庭玫瑰   PiPi
此人于五年前被政府俘获
who was captured by the government five years ago.
拉马尔以其极端的观点和做法闻名
Ramal is known for his extreme views and practices,
翻译     肉塔   徐棒棒   ABCpril   木浅
从用少女当性奴隶
from using young girls as sex slaves,
到打着中世纪正义的标签
to a medieval brand of justice that
包括在街上公开施行斩首和处决
includes public beheadings and executions in the street.
校对 不高兴童鞋 木浅 蓝色薄荷 普利星布里狗 冰卡
拉马尔目前被关在
Ramal is currently being held in Yemen's
也门臭名昭著的监狱 奥杰吉亚监狱
most notorious penitentiary, Ogygia Prison.
时间轴    姜姜 大葱 壬虚浪影
也门 奥杰吉亚监狱
后期     梁良糖    吉吉
总监     何何也爱折千纸鹤
时机到了
This is it.
维普 上来
Whip, get up here.
现在进行吗
Is it happening?
你不会丢下我们的 对吧
You are not going to leave us, are you?
如果叛军占领这座城市 我们就死定了
If the rebels take the city, we're dead.
你已经跟我们说了一千次了 希德
You've told us that a thousand times, Sid.
你都成唐僧了 安全了吗
You're a broken record. Is it clear?
好的 安全了
Okay, it's clear.
■
人人词典
使用人人词典查词学习，美剧原声朗读与例句场景
Prison Break
维普 拿着
Whip. Come on.
熄灯后 你跟上
Lights go out... ...you follow.
快点儿
Come on.
要是像以前一样
Would have made it so much easier
只有你我不是要容易得多吗
if it was just you and me like it was on all the other ones.
这次没那么容易
Nothing is easy on this one.
可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
一分钟
One minute.
木板横在缺口处
Board spans the gap.
好的
Okay.
毯子盖住电线
Blanket covers the wire.
现在就等那些灯熄了
Now it's about those lights going out.
二十四小时前他没有闪灯
He didn't flash it 24 hours before.
- 那本来是信号  - 要有信心
- That's supposed to be the signal.  - Have faith.
连着七个晚上吗
Seven straight nights?
没有信号 灯从来没熄过
No signal, no lights getting turned out?
那些攻击也越来越近了
Those strikes are getting closer, too.
那些灯不会熄了
Those lights aren't going out.
- 灯不会熄了  - 得回去了
- Lights aren't going out.  - Got to go back.
不如试试直接跑
Maybe make a run for it.
距离太远了
Too much ground to cover.
我们到不了缺口就会被射杀
They'll shoot us down before we make the gap.
那我们计划怎么办 放弃 然后死掉
What's the plan then? Give up and die?
我不能再等上四年
I can't wait another four years.
本来说好只有一周的
It was supposed to be one week.
波塞冬把我们丢在这里等死
Poseidon has left us here to die.
我还有一步棋可以走
We still got one card left to play.
我本来不想这么做 但它已经开始了
I didn't want to play it, but it's already in motion.
我们走吧
Let's go.
卡尼尔·乌提斯被投进奥杰吉亚
Apparently, Kaniel Outis was thrown into Ogygia
是因为对抗政府
for crimes against the government.
不久以后 他因为企图逃跑
Shortly after, he was captured
被抓住 之后关了禁闭
trying to escape, and thrown into solitary.
他们最近刚释放他回囚区
They just released him into gen pop recently.
叫他迈克尔 行吗
Call him Michael, will you?
那为什么他见到我们时不肯承认
But why didn't he acknowledge us when he saw us?
站住
Stop!
给我回来
Get back here!
- 那孩子在监视我们  - 是的
- Kid was spying on us.  - Yeah.
他还在门垫下面留了个东西
And he left something under the doormat.
找到光之酋长
我就会重获自由
越 狱 第五季第二集
这是迈克尔的笔迹
This is Michael's handwriting.
天鹅是他的标志 他在找我们
Swan was his calling card. He's reaching out to us.
但他干嘛搞得这么神秘
But why is he being so mysterious?
以前 他有没有说话这么不直白过
Back in the day, he never talked to you straight,
我是说不直白到用暗号的程度
as in not in code?
他是担心有人会拦截他的信息
He's worried about someone intercepting his message.
好吧 但这信息是什么意思
Yeah, but what does it mean?
我不知道 但他认为我们知道
I don't know, but we're supposed to know.
光之酋长 光之酋长
"Sheik of Light." Sheik of Light.
听起来像是那种在山顶上
That sounds like a guy on a mountain peak
和神交流的人
communing with God.
我们得找人帮忙
Yeah, we got to get help.
- 没人能帮我们  - 希巴
- We're out of help.  - Sheba.
她认为我在帮助恐怖分子
She's thinks I'm abetting a terrorist.
那你就得向她证明并非如此
Well, then you have to convince her that you're not.
你必须离开 爸爸
You have got to leave, Papa.
- 我不会逃跑的  - 政府正在被攻击
- I will not run away.  - The government is being targeted.
你在被攻击
You are being targeted.
我是个无名小卒
I'm a no one.
你对他们来说等同于政府
You are government to them.
你不理解做一个也门人的意义
You don't understand being a Yemeni.
在祖国需要你的时候 你转身就跑吗
You would run away when she needs you the most?
我只知道我们死了对国家是毫无价值的
I understand that we are no good to this country dead.
爸爸 留得青山在 不怕没柴烧
Papa, there will come a time.
我们逃去海外 和流亡政府汇合
We go abroad, regroup with an exile government.
哪有钱供我们逃呢 孩子
With what money, girl?
需要的这笔钱是你两年的工资
It would cost two years' salary.
我宁可直面敌人而亡 也不愿逃跑
I'd rather die with my face to the enemy than to run away.
爸爸
Papa...
我建议你尽快离开这个国家
I suggest you leave this country as quickly as you can.
他来干嘛
What's he doing here?
我朋友需要你的帮忙
My friend needs your help.
我给了他帮助
I gave him my help.
你没告诉我他在和我的敌人合作
You didn't tell me he was working with the enemy.
这个你声称是你弟弟的男人
This man you claim is your brother,
卡尼尔·乌提斯 和反叛军合作
Kaniel Outis, worked with the rebels.
- 他叫迈克尔·斯科菲尔德  - 我不在乎
- His name's Michael Scofield.  - I don't care!
不是卡尼尔·乌提斯
Not Kaniel Outis!
现在不管你说什么
There's nothing you can say to me
我都不会帮你好吗
that will make me help you, okay?
是吗
Is that right?
这些足够带你全家离开这个国家了吧
This enough to get your family out of the country?
先给我办这件事
Deliver me this first.
伊萨卡 纽约
准备好了吗 宝贝
Ready, love?
我们昨天在奥吉杰亚监狱录下了这个
- 那是什么  - 这是...
- What's that?  - It's, uh... it's
这是你林肯伯伯发来的东西
something your Uncle Lincoln sent.
- 来吧  - 我不想去
- Here.  - I don't want to go.
我想和你在一起
I want to stay with you.
你得去上学
You got to go to school.
下课的时候我会在这里等着你
And I'm gonna be right here when the bell rings.
好吗 你从台阶上走下来
Okay? You walk down those steps,
直接跳进车里面 好吗
you hop straight into the car. Yeah?
我爱你
I love you.
祝你一天愉快
Make it a great day.
我收到你得消息了
I got the note.
我明白 迈克尔
I got the note, Michael.
我们会把你从那儿弄出来
We're going to get you out of here.
听着 我不叫迈克尔
Look, my name isn't Michael,
我也不知道你是谁
and I don't know who you are.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你知道我成了有名的经济学家吗
You know I'm a noted economist?
我是说报纸上是这么写的
I mean, that's what it says in the paper.
“著名经济学家在家遇袭“
"Noted Economist Attackedin Home."
我都不知道经济学家都能上报纸
I didn't even know economists made the news.
但愿没有下次了
That's the first and last time, hopefully.
我一直想把这一切搞清楚
I've been trying to piece this thing together.
你还得的那些政府的人吗
You remember those government guys,
那些智囊团的家伙
those think tank guys,
想向我请教博弈论的东西
trying to pick my brain about game theory,
他们怎么才能把它用于外交政策上
how they could use it for foreign policy?
记得 他们烦透你了 对吗
Yeah, you bored the hell out of 'em, right?
没错 但是我是不是听了不该听的东西
Yeah, okay, but I mean, did I hear something I shouldn't have?
我不知道 你有吗
I don't know. Did you?
比如谁刺杀了肯尼迪
Like who shot JFK?
我是认真的
I am trying to be serious here.
不 你是不是止痛药吃多了
No, you're doped up on painkillers
而且你想太多了
and you're thinking too much.
我保证这和你一点关系也没有
I promise this has nothing to do with you.
好好休息 我要去…
You rest. I'm going to, um...
我还有些事要办
I'm gonna run some errands,
然后我再去看你 好吗
and then I'm gonna come visit you, okay?
好的爱你
Okay. Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
好了 没问题 谢谢
Okay, no problem. Thanks.
我之前打电话问起关于一名
Hi. I, uh, I called earlier about
在中东失踪的美国公民
a missing U.S. citizen in the Middle East.
没错 我是亨利·岸田
Yes. I'm Henry Kishida.
我带你去局长办公室
Let me walk you to the director's office.
这种情况不常见
It's an unusual situation,
你应该感到庆幸
which you can appreciate,
毕竟你丈夫在法律上己经宣告死亡
since your husband is declared legally dead,
而且你提到这个人
and the person that you're referring to
使用的是另一个名字
goes by another name.
这里交给我吧 亨利
I'll take it from here, Henry.
你好吗 莎拉
How are you, Sara?
凯勒曼
Kellerman?
你们谈吧 有什么需要叫我 长官
I'll leave you two be. Let me know if you need anything, sir.
抱歉 我怎么又和你扯上关系了
Sorry, how did I end up with you again?
你向国务院提出求助
You asked for the State Department's help.
我想要国务院的帮忙 不是你
I wanted the State Department, not you.
你以前身份那么多
Yeah, you've lived so many lives,
我不知道这次你扮演谁了
I don't know who you are.
你的处境不也一样吗 不是吗
That'd be a consistent theme for you, wouldn't it,
你嫁了一个根本不存在的男人
given that you were married to a man who never existed?
你这话是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是你该进来 我会把关于
It means you should come in and let me enlighten you
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的事都告诉你
to all things Michael Scofield...
或者叫卡尼尔·乌提斯
Or should I say Kaniel Outis?
你不该喝瓶装水的
You shouldn't drink
里面都是二恶英 避孕药…
bottled water... the dioxins, the BPAs in there...
很感激你关心我
I'm touched by your concern.
请坐
Have a seat.
好 谢谢
Good, thank you.
你知道的 莎拉
You know, Sara...
你和我有段… 波折的过往
you and I have... a checkered past.
但我现在就是个无趣之人 而且…
But I am evermore a boring guy now, and...
被生活磨平了棱角 相信我
mellowed by life, trust me.
如果你有关于迈克尔的消息想告诉我
If you have something you want to tell me about Michael,
就赶紧说吧
I'd sure love to hear it.
我们接到你的电话之后 岸田就进行了调查
Okay. When your call came in and Kishida processed it...
我就说些让我们甚为震惊的
well, let's just say there are certain keywords
关键词好了
that get our system buzzing pretty quickly.
卡尼尔·乌提斯…
Kaniel Outis...
其实 我实在
Actually, can't stand it
受不了你用瓶子喝水
watching you drink out of that.
岸田
Hey, Kishida?
能帮莎拉倒杯水吗
Could you bring Sara a glass for her water, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
卡尼尔·乌提斯…
Kaniel Outis...
是一名因杀害
is a known terrorist,
中情局高级官员
ties to ISIL, wanted in the killing
而被通缉的ISIL恐怖分子
of a senior CIA official.
迈克尔不会杀人的
Michael's no killer.
这就是问题所在
You see, that's the problem.
因为卡尼尔·乌提斯会
Because Kaniel Outis is.
- 谢谢  - 不用谢
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
而且…
And...
这就是卡尼尔·乌提斯
this is Kaniel Outis.
简直荒唐
That's ridiculous.
官方记录显示...
The record here at State says
这就是卡尼尔·乌提斯的长相
that... that's Kaniel Outis's face.
好吧 但你我都知道迈克尔·斯科菲尔德是谁
Okay, but you and I both know who Michael Scofield was.
不 那只是回忆
No, that's just a memory.
官方记录 包括他的过去
The official record... history...
都已经不同了
It says otherwise now.
你想想幕后主使 那才叫恐怖
Now, that's scary, to think who could be behind that.
因为只有那种厉害的人
Because only somebody very formidable
才能做到
would be capable
在官方层面为一个人更改身份
of officially turning one man into another.
比如像迈克尔那样的天才
It would take a genius... like Michael.
你是在暗示这是他自己策划的吗
You're insinuating that he did this?
他消失了
He disappeared,
就这样放弃了他的生活吗
just quit on his life?
我和你一样想要知道答案
I want answers just like you do.
谁能办到这种事
Who's capable of this?
全世界能做到的人屈指可数
Only a handful of people in the world.
莎拉 莎拉
Sara? Sara!
我们应该还有一天 顶多两天
I figure we got a day, maybe two,
就能离开这鬼地方
tops, to get out of this hole.
等到那时 我们要么是被流弹炸死...
At that point, either the shelling gets us...
要么就是被ISIL恐怖组织抓走
or ISIL does.
你一点都不害怕吗
Does any of this phase you at all?
我们马上就要死在这里了
The fact that we're gonna die in here?
我们不会死 我们会逃出去的
We're not gonna die. We're still getting out.
我们所有人
All of us.
怎么逃 通过房顶吗
How's that? The roof?
- 房顶行不通的  - 能行得通
- The roof ain't happening.  - The roof is happening.
我们没有时间再想一套越狱方案了
We don't have time to come up with another escape plan.
所以你确实怕了
So you are nervous.
真好 现在我知道我在劫难逃了
Great, now I know I'm in deep crap.
我做这些只是为了钱
I'm only doing this for the money.
别以为咱俩关系突然变好了
Don't think you and I are suddenly good.
你只管把酋长带来就行
You just deliver me the sheik.
酋长们离这里很远
The sheiks are well away from here.
在沙漠高原
High desert.
而且我从没听说过
And I've never heard of one
有叫光之酋长的
being referred to as Sheik of Light.
也就是说这可能是暗语
Which means it's probably a code.
她真了解你弟
She knows your brother.
这条纸带
This tape...
是唯一一个不属于这张纸的东西
It's the only thing that doesn't belong.
你弟弟喜欢说谜语 是不是
Your brother speaks in riddles, does he?
有可能是盲文 或者是摩尔斯码
Maybe it's Braille or, uh, Morse.
或者只是数字
Or just numbers.
我觉得是个电话号码
I think it's a phone number.
语音信箱
Voice mail.
穆罕默德·埃尔·突尼斯
Mohammad El-Tunis.
萨那的电气工程主任
Director of Electrical Works in Sana'a.
电气工程主任
Director of Electrical Works.
“光之酋长”
"Sheik of Light."
电气工程部
萨那
感谢您百忙之中来见我们
Thanks for taking the time to see us.
人都哪去了
Where is everybody?
他们事先就逃走了
They are fleeing ahead of the advance.
我们一直在找他
We have been trying to reach him.
我们只知道他去了郊区
All we know is that he went to the suburbs
去找他的女儿
to try to find his daughter.
你有她的地址吗
Do you have an address for her?
我们试着打过电话了 但是没人接
We tried calling her, but no answer.
这是地址
Address is here.
你们不会是想去找他吧
You are not going to try to find him, are you?
愿真主与你们同在
God be with you, then.
地址圈出来了
Circled the address.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
你跟我们一起走
You're coming with us.
如果你以为我会去郊区的话
If you think I'm going into the suburbs,
那你们就是疯了
you're crazy.
郊区怎么了
What's wrong with the suburbs?
郊区在那边
The suburbs are out there.
战争的前线
The front line of the war.
很高兴认识你 本杰明
Nice knowing you, Benjamin.
我希望下次见面的时候状况能好些
I hope next time it's under better circumstances.
- 付钱吧  - 你得把我们弄过关卡
- Pay up.  - You have to get us past the checkpoint.
我们俩美国人 没有你我俩啥都办不成
Two Americans... we'll never make it without you.
我可不想自杀
I am not getting myself killed.
付钱
Pay up.
给我酋长
Deliver the sheik.
我就给你钱
Then you get your money.
上车
Get in.
喂
Yes?
看一下你的邮箱 莎拉
You should check your e-mail, Sara.
我看的这是什么
What am I looking at?
一个猎人四年前拍的图片
Footage captured by a hunter four years ago.
用一种挂在树上的运动传感器
One of those motion sensor devices you hang on trees,
可以不间断地拍摄谢捕食的动物
takes intermittent photos of prey.
猎人有一天早晨发现了这些图片
Hunter comes out one morning, finds these images.
这就是我跟你说的那起谋杀
This is the killing I was telling you about.
受害者是哈伦·盖恩斯 中情局副局长
The victim's Harlan Gaines, Deputy Chief of the CIA.
然而杀手…
And the killer...
你也看到了
well, you can see,
就是被我们称为迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的人
it's who we call Michael Scofield,
或者卡尼尔·乌提斯
or Kaniel Outis, or...
他们对林肯用的也是这招
This is exactly what they did to Lincoln.
第二天就有血迹证据了
And then there's the blood evidence the next day.
卡尼尔或者迈克尔上了去也门的飞机
Kaniel or Michael or whatever gets on a flight to Yemen.
他下飞机的时候我们差点就抓住他了
We all most nail him when he lands.
他跑了
He gets away.
但是他的包没跑
His luggage doesn't
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
最新海外影视剧下载
里面的衣服上全是盖恩斯的血
and Gaines' blood is all over the clothes inside.
证据确凿
The evidence is overwhelming.
不论你想叫他什么名字
Whatever name you want to call him,
迈克尔都是凶手 萨拉
Michael's a murderer, Sara.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
你还好吗
You all right?
这一套吗
Oh, this old thing?
我挺好的
Yeah, I'm doing fine.
发生什么了
What's going on?
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
但你可能
It's probably something
不想谈论这件事
you're not gonna want to talk about.
但我真的很需要你清晰的思路
I could really use your clarity right now.
事关迈克尔
It's about Michael.
我还是想知道他是怎么把这东西弄进来的
Still want to know how he got that in here.
跟狱警睡了
Hugging naked with the guards.
肯定的吧
Got to be, right?
那是什么
What the hell is that?
《我们是冠军》
"We are the Champions."
困在这么个厕所一样的地方 还看皇后乐队
You get stuck in a Porta-Potty like this, you go Queen?
怎么不看点
I mean, where are the girls
有女人的小黄片呢
riding the washing machines, right?
再看我的屏幕 我就用它戳瞎你的狗眼
Look at my screen again, this goes in your eye.
大千世界无奇不有
You know, the world never ceases to amaze.
被关在中东的监狱里
You get stuck in a Middle Eastern prison,
而里面最混蛋的却是个韩国人
the biggest S.O.B. is a Korean.
他停药犯瘾了
He's in withdrawal.
因为我们是
Cause we're the champions
世界冠军
of the world...
知道吗 他是这世界上
You know, he's the biggest collector
最大的皇后乐队周边收藏家
of Queen paraphernalia in the world.
据说他首尔的家就是个佛莱迪·摩克瑞的神龛
They say his house in Seoul is a shrine to Freddy Mercury.
那他为什么被关进来
And he got in here how?
身份盗窃
Identity theft.
他经常坐在自家沙发上
Apparently he used to sit on his couch,
黑进世界各国的高额网络账户
hack high net worth accounts all over the world.
然后收藏悍马车 直升飞机
Turned it into a collection of Hummers, helicopters
当然还有佛莱迪·摩克瑞的骨灰
and, apparently, Freddy Mercury's ashes.
等等 你是说他火化的骨灰吗
Wait, you mean like his burnt-up body?
据说佛莱迪被火化了 但骨灰却不见了
The story is Freddy's cremated, but his ashes go missing.
至今没有人知道下落
To this day no one knows where they are.
有一次雅嗑嗨了之后告诉我是他买下了
Ja admitted to me once when he was high he bought them.
两百万美金
Two million bucks.
他家里可是存着皇后乐队的主唱
He's got Queen's lead singer in his family room.
你是怎么知道这些的
How exactly do you know all this?
我问他的
I asked him.
他没犯瘾的时候真的是个好人
He's a real mensch when he's not in withdrawal.
我都不知道你跟他说过话
I didn't know you talked to him.
赞啊
Amazing.
我还以为我懂你了 原来我不懂
Just when I think I know your game, I don't.
你懂我的 维普
You know my game, Whip.
就这个“维普”
See, right there, "Whip."
我都不知道你为什么这么叫我
I don't even know why you call me that.
因为你是我的优势
Because you're my whip hand.
我的杀手锏
My ace in the hole.
好吧
Yeah, sure, okay.
在博弈论中你需要成为两面派
See, in game theory, it serves you to be two-faced.
和每个人做朋友 直到你再不需要为止
Be everyone's friend till the moment you're not.
你要让大家都爱你 在关键时刻
You make them love you so much that when they're up against it,
大家对你的忠诚会让他们
their loyalty will make them act
做出违反自己最佳利益的事情
against their own best interests.
这就是博弈论
That's game theory.
冷静 理智 专注于赢
A cold, rational focus on winning.
尽管需要牺牲其他所有人
Even if it's at everyone else's expense.
我想知道的是他想得到什么
What I'm trying to understand is what he stands to gain.
离开他的家人 用新的身份生活
Leaving his family, and-and the new identity.
从你告诉我的那点事来看 他变了
According to the little you've told me, he was different.
他总是有自己的小算盘 不是吗
Always an agenda, right?
是
Yeah.
他显然很爱你
I mean, he apparently loved you.
他当然爱你了
Of course he loved you.
他怎么会不爱你呢
How could he not?
但他也想要你为他打开
But he also wanted you to open that door
监狱的那扇门
in the prison for him.
在真正的博弈论中
I mean, true game theory,
任何事任何人
everything, everyone
都是一个偶然事件
is a contingency.
你会遇见别人 把他们带入自己的生活
You meet people, you bring them into your life
你会和他们一直搞好关系
and you keep them percolating until the moment
直到最终需要为自己而利用这些关系
you need to manipulate the relationship to your advantage.
我不是在评判他 我不是那样的人
I'm not judging, you know? That's not my thing.
- 我知道  - 你了解我的 但是
- I know.  - You know me. But...
陷得太深
schema as deep
算得太深 到最后
and as calculating as that can, in the end,
会把人逼疯
spin a man off into madness.
最开始他可能觉得为了顾全大局
He might initially think smaller evils are okay
可以纵容小恶
in the service of a greater good.
比如帮林肯越狱
Like breaking Lincoln out of prison.
不过善与恶有时难以分辨
But the dance of good and evil could become jumbled,
以至对他人的操控
and the manipulation itself becomes
成了最重要的事
the most important thing.
人会变得一心求胜
Becomes about winning
而不去考虑胜利本身是对是错
rather than whether the game should be won at all.
我从未见你这样害怕过
I don't think I've seen you this scared before.
他们说 这次斋月为示宽恕
They say, for Ramadan, as an act of forgiveness,
他们要释放
they're going to release
那里面关着的所有被禁闭的囚犯
all prisoners from solitary over there back into general population.
他们是坏人中穷凶极恶之人
Worst of the worst.
ISIL恐怖组织狂热分子
ISIL fanatics.
阿布·拉马尔
Abu Ramal.
你知道他们会杀了我的
They're going to kill me, you know.
我因为是同性恋
Government gave me 20 years
被政府判了20年
for homosexuality.
但是那里面的怪物
But the monsters in there,
拉马尔和他的手下
Ramal and his men,
不会让我活过20分钟
won't let me live 20 minutes.
拜托告诉我
Please tell me
你仍然打算把我们弄出这个地方
you still plan on getting us out of here.
你当时负责断掉电源
You were responsible for killing the lights,
而你的光之酋长却在关键时刻
and then your Sheik of Light went missing
不知所踪
at exactly the wrong time.
我不知道他发生了什么事
I don't know what happened to him.
也许我能想到别的办法
Maybe I can find another way.
有件事你倒是能做
There is something you could do.
给我一片口香糖
Give me a piece of that gum.
凭一片口香糖就能让我们越狱吗
Piece of gum is going to get us out of prison?
它将成为导火索
It'll start the process.
朋友 有时我都不知道是你的计划更大
Sometimes, my friend, I can't tell which is bigger,
还是你的谎言更大
your plans or your lies.
我可记住了 你说我是个骗子
I take that personally, you calling me a liar.
我会让你见识到 就像蝴蝶效应一样
And I'm gonna show you, just like the butterfly's wings,
这片口香糖会引发一系列事件
this piece of gum is gonna start a sequence of events
最终会让我们来到监狱高墙之外
that will finish on the other side of the world.
给我电池
Battery, please.
监狱版打火机
Prison lighter.
维普 我需要你的袜子
Whip, I need your socks.
希德 装水罐头
Sid, water can.
外面情况如何
How we doing out there?
没问题 动作快
We're all good. Quick though.
好了
Okay.
你确定要这么做吗
You sure about this?
我们没有时间了
There's no time left.
这座城市快要崩溃了
The city's about to collapse.
非常时期 非常手段
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
好了
Ah! Got it.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
快 快 快
Go, go, go.
狱警
Guards!
有人生病了
We got a sick one in here.
怎么回事
What is this?
他在发高烧 需要去趟医务室
He's burning up, he needs the infirmary.
拜托了
Please.
我们到了
This is it.
政府控制区边界
Limit of government control.
外面都是ISIL恐怖组织的领地
Anything after this is ISIL territory.
停车
Stop.
让我来谈
Let me do the talking.
他说我们是白人 是女人
He's says us being Westerners, a woman...
一旦进去 就出不来了
we go inside, we are not coming back.
他们不放我们出去
They're not letting us through.
告诉他 我赌500美金能安全返回
Tell him I bet $500 bucks we'll make it back in one piece.
他没有500美金来和你赌
He doesn't have $500 to bet.
不重要
It doesn't matter.
我们要是回不来 这就是他的钱了
We don't make it back, he keeps it.
他说我们这是去送死
He says we have a death wish.
行了吧
Fine.
这座城市曾经很美丽 充满生机
The city used to be beautiful, alive.
看看他们都干了什么
Look what they've done to it.
他们在到处画阿布·拉马尔的画像
They're putting up portraits of Abu Ramal.
他自从被关进奥杰吉亚监狱后
He's only gotten more powerful
就变得越来越有势力
since he got locked up in Ogygia.
他要是出狱了就更不敢想像
God help us if he gets out.
ISIL的
ISIL.
我们需要停下来 下车
We're gonna get stopped. Get down.
快下车
Down now.
藏好
Cover up.
真不敢相信
Can't believe this.
我认识他
I know him.
身份证件
是你
雷扎
Reza.
现在是阿布·阿米尔
It's Abu Amir now.
你在城郊干什么 希巴
What are you doing in the suburbs, Sheba?
拐错弯了
Took a wrong turn.
你把头发罩起来了
You got your hair covered up.
很好
That's good.
终于找到真主了吗
Finally find God?
不是你的真主
Not your God.
世上只有一位真主
There is only one God.
我们会拿下这座城市 你知道的
We're gonna take the city, you know.
只要你老实
You be nice...
或许我能让你成为一个好女人
maybe I'll make a good woman of you.
原谅你内心的魔鬼
Forgive the devil in you.
我可以现在就掉头
Why don't I just turn around now?
我们原谅彼此
We forgive each other.
忘记彼此的存在
Forget each other ever existed.
美人不是那么容易忘记的
Beauty is not so easily forgotten.
博爱的小子
Lover boy!
我们得走了
We have to go.
政府军到阿克萨公园了
Government's moving in at Aksa Park.
别管她了
Cut her loose.
滚出我们的地盘
Get the hell off our territory.
他们走了
They are gone.
我们要赶快
We have to hurry.
他刚才没杀我是我们运气好
We're lucky he didn't kill me right then.
为什么
Why?
没准我将来会告诉你
Maybe I'll tell you one day.
他们正在摧毁我们的城市
They're destroying our city.
你的那些ISIL朋友正在摧毁我们的城市
Your ISIL friends are destroying our city.
而你现在却跑来寻求帮助
And you come in here wanting help.
随便给我点什么吧
Just give me a little something.
这里有医生吗 我正发高烧
Is there a doctor here? I'm burning up.
你早该想到有今天了
You should have thought about that
在你给他们提供武器的时候
when you supplied guns to them,
在你杀害那些好人的时候
assassinated good men.
那些指控是一个误会
Those charges were a misunderstanding.
真主 卡尼尔·乌提斯说这是一场误会
Oh, Allah. Kaniel Outis says it was a misunderstanding.
那么你进到监狱的那一刻
Was it also a misunderstanding
就在企图越狱
when you tried to escape the moment
这是不是也是一场误会啊
you got into this prison? Hmm?
诚实的人不会去越狱
An honest man doesn't try to escape.
而是会叫律师
He asks for a lawyer. But you,
但你自打进来的第一周就盘算着越狱
you tried to escape the very first week.
要是我能做主 我会让你一辈子关禁闭
I'd have left you in solitary forever if it was up to me.
这个街区的最后一个地址
The address at the end of the block.
是反叛军
Rebels...
就在房子前面
right in front of the house.
这帮浑蛋
Son of a bitch.
在这个国家办什么事情能容易
Anything easy in this country?
问题是酋长究竟在不在里面
The question is: is the sheik even inside?
只有一个办法能找到答案
Only one way to find out.
他们要是在这上面发现我们
They find us up here,
我们就没有解释的机会了
there's no explaining ourselves.
我们就死定了
We're all dead.
别出声
Quiet.
你们不是ISIL的人
You... You are not ISIL?
不 你是穆罕默德·埃尔·突尼斯 对吧
No. But you're Mohammad El-Tunis, I take it?
附近还有人
我们是市中心来的
We are from the city center.
来救你出去
We are here to get you out.
除非让我女儿也一起走
Not without my daughter.
我们可以带上她 她人呢
We can bring her. Where is she?
- 她就在外面  - 哪里
- She's out there.  - Where?
在街对面那间学校的地窖里
In the basement of the schoolyard, across the street.
ISIL恐怖组织一来 她就困在那里
Pinned since ISIL arrived.
我本想去救她出来
I came to get her out.
结果我也被困住了
And I got pinned, too.
无意打击你 林肯
I hate to say it, Linc,
但我估计我们也会被困住
but I think we might've just got pinned as well.
你没事吧
You okay?
你看着像想要挨几刀
You look like you could use a few sharp edges
直接升天的人
knocked off your world.
你看起来也不怎么样
You don't look so good yourself.
你在也门最想要什么
Say what you want about Yemen,
给起药品来他们倒是不吝啬
they're not shy about prescriptions.
这是个好玩意儿 吗啡仿制药
It's the good stuff. Morphine derivative.
我要用你的手机和信用卡
I need access to your cell phone and a credit card number.
干吗
Why?
叫份披萨
I want to order a pizza.
有个后门通往学校
There's a back door, toward the schoolhouse.
跟我来
Come on.
太迟了
Too late.
去屋顶上
Go to the rooftops.
他们的人遍布罗威
They're all over the Rover.
我们进不去的
We'll never get to it.
我可以到那辆小货车上
I can get in that pickup,
冲出去 制造骚乱
make a ruckus on my way out.
顺利的话 他们会把我团包围
Any luck, they'll be all over me.
然后你们趁没人直接冲出去
Then you got a clean shot to the Rover.
走 快走
Go. Go!
没有女儿 我哪儿也不去
I'm not leaving without my daughter.
你们不知道那些人渣都用些什么手段
You don't know what ISIL will do to her
“教育”那些女孩
for educating those girls.
我会救她出来 我保证
I'll get her out, I promise.
- 快走  - 好好
- Go!  - Okay! Okay.
你父亲让我来的 我来救你出去
Your father sent me. I'm getting you out of here.
快出来 快出来
Come on! Come on!
趴下 别起来
Get down! Stay down!
他一定会成功
He's got to make it.
你必须成功一定
You know you got to make it. Come on.
他来了  来了
There he is! There he is!
太他妈好了
Yeah, baby!
不 情况不妙
Oh, no. This isn't good.
情况非常不妙
This isn't good.
政府设的关卡
This government checkpoint.
他们会误会我们是自杀炸弹袭击者
They'll think we're suicide bombers.
我们得停车
We have to stop.
你他妈疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
别开枪
Don't shoot at us!
别开枪 别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
趴下
Stay down!
我也很开心
I'm so happy, too.
抱歉
Forgive me, uh...
她们的父母都被杀害了
Their parents have been killed.
我正想办法怎么才能帮到她们
I'm trying to figure out how I can help them.
她们可以暂时留在这儿
They can stay here for now.
只要告诉我你在奥杰吉亚招惹了谁
As long as you tell me who you know in Ogygia,
他们为什么这么想抓你
and why they want you so bad.
我只是个…
I'm a man with, uh...
“问题孩子”的父亲
troublesome children.
他们是很好的孩子
They're beautiful.
但可能对于这个国家来说太离经叛道了
But perhaps too modern for this country.
我女儿想要教女孩们读书
My daughter tries to educate girls.
我儿子
And my son,
他爱上了一个男人
he falls in love with another man.
他们因此判了他二十年
They gave him 20 years in Ogygia Prison.
几周前我想去看他
I went to visit him a few weeks ago.
他说可能有办法出去
He said, maybe there is a way out.
一个我能帮上忙的方法
A way I could help.
一个男人不能眼看着家人送死
A man is not a man if he would let his family die.
你答应了帮他
You agreed to help him.
那怎么帮
How?
他说只要我能想办法让全城停电
He said if I could arrange a blackout,
他 他认识的一个人就能帮他逃出来
he... he knew someone who could get him out.
是个美国人吗
An American?
不知道
I don't know.
我本应该在一周前就安排好
I-I was supposed to do this a week ago,
但我女儿又出了这状况
but then this happened with my daughter.
感谢上帝你们帮了我们
Thank God you found us.
现在还有时间来实施计划
There's still time to do it.
他们正在监狱里等你
They're waiting for you in there.
那我现在就得走了
Then I have to go now.
他说要我要准确地在停电的
He said I was to give a signal
24小时前给他们发一个信号
exactly 24 hours before the blackout.
我会让电网跳两次
I will pulse the power grid twice.
恐怕这城市撑不到24小时了
This city may not have 24 hours in it.
再见 小家伙们
Bye, guys.
拜拜
Bye.
是人都知道我看人不准
God knows I'm no perfect judge of character,
但对迈克尔不会
but Michael?
要是他们说的是真的…
If any of what they're saying is true...
所以还有很多细节需要核实 莎拉
So there's more to find out, Sara.
重要的是 不管结果如何
I mean, the important thing is that
你都会度过这一关的
you are gonna survive this, however it turns out.
而且我们会支持你的 好吗
And we're here for you. Okay?
- 我们走吧  - 谢谢
- Let's go.  - Thank you.
联系我 好吗
Call me, okay?
好
Yeah.
我进去找一下麦克 好吗
Hey, can I just scoop Mike real quick?
所有孩子都出来了
All the kids have been released.
你没接到他吗
You don't have him?
麦克
Mike?
- 我去找这边  - 好
- I'll go this way.  - Okay, yeah.
麦克
Mike?
你看见麦克了吗
Hey, hey, have you seen Mike?
麦克
Mike!
你...
There...
你在干什么 吓死我了
What are you doing? You scared me.
我在看那个人去哪了
I was looking for where the man went.
什么人 宝贝
What man, baby?
给我这个的人
The man that gave me this.
披萨外卖员
The pizza man.
The pizza man?
众生皆隐藏 风暴即将至
迈克尔
Michael.
你卷进了什么事呢
What are you into?
ISIL恐怖组织每时每刻都在逼近
ISIL is getting closer by the hour.
这里的叛乱者也都清楚
And the rebels in here know it.
等ISIL占领了这里 他们就会杀了我们
When they take over, they'll kill all of us.
异教徒 罪人 外国人
Infidels, the sinners, the foreigners.
真主安拉
Praise Allah.
有人找到了我的父亲
Someone found my father.
那意味着越狱开始了
Means the escape is on.
24小时以后
24 hours from now.
但也许太迟了
But this may be too late.
斋月已经开始了
Ramadan has begun.
守卫要释放囚犯了
The guards are releasing the prisoners.
阿布-拉马尔和他的手下
Abu Ramal and his men,
他们会杀了我
they'll kill me.
还有你
And you.
终于见到你了 兄弟
可我们还没自由呢
你为我们安排好出去的路了吗
■
微信扫瞄
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔
m 350 100 l 350 110 l 360 110 l 360 100 m 360 100 m 100 320 l 100 330 l 110 330 l 110 320 m 110 320 m 260 230 l 260 240 l 270 240 l 270 230 m 270 230 m 220 230 l 220 240 l 230 240 l 230 230 m 230 230 m 270 300 l 270 310 l 280 310 l 280 300 m 280 300 m 360 60 l 360 70 l 370 70 l 370 60 m 370 60 m 130 40 l 130 50 l 140 50 l 140 40 m 140 40 m 180 350 l 180 360 l 190 360 l 190 350 m 190 350 m 190 340 l 190 350 l 200 350 l 200 340 m 200 340 m 150 260 l 150 270 l 160 270 l 160 260 m 160 260 m 40 210 l 40 220 l 50 220 l 50 210 m 50 210 m 180 50 l 180 60 l 190 60 l 190 50 m 190 50 m 160 210 l 160 220 l 170 220 l 170 210 m 170 210 m 290 190 l 290 200 l 300 200 l 300 190 m 300 190 m 170 240 l 170 250 l 180 250 l 180 240 m 180 240 m 300 160 l 300 170 l 310 170 l 310 160 m 310 160 m 330 210 l 330 220 l 340 220 l 340 210 m 340 210 m 70 60 l 70 70 l 80 70 l 80 60 m 80 60 m 340 180 l 340 190 l 350 190 l 350 180 m 350 180 m 320 140 l 320 150 l 330 150 l 330 140 m 330 140 m 90 280 l 90 290 l 100 290 l 100 280 m 100 280 m 330 150 l 330 160 l 340 160 l 340 150 m 340 150 m 240 180 l 240 190 l 250 190 l 250 180 m 250 180 m 220 140 l 220 150 l 230 150 l 230 140 m 230 140 m 270 230 l 270 240 l 280 240 l 280 230 m 280 230 m 250 190 l 250 200 l 260 200 l 260 190 m 260 190 m 260 160 l 260 170 l 270 170 l 270 160 m 270 160 m 130 130 l 130 140 l 140 140 l 140 130 m 140 130 m 270 130 l 270 140 l 280 140 l 280 130 m 280 130 m 140 180 l 140 190 l 150 190 l 150 180 m 150 180 m 150 190 l 150 200 l 160 200 l 160 190 m 160 190 m 130 230 l 130 240 l 140 240 l 140 230 m 140 230 m 280 250 l 280 260 l 290 260 l 290 250 m 290 250 m 160 120 l 160 130 l 170 130 l 170 120 m 170 120 m 290 200 l 290 210 l 300 210 l 300 200 m 300 200 m 310 100 l 310 110 l 320 110 l 320 100 m 320 100 m 60 160 l 60 170 l 70 170 l 70 160 m 70 160 m 330 80 l 330 90 l 340 90 l 340 80 m 340 80 m 70 210 l 70 220 l 80 220 l 80 210 m 80 210 m 200 110 l 200 120 l 210 120 l 210 110 m 210 110 m 100 180 l 100 190 l 110 190 l 110 180 m 110 180 m 340 310 l 340 320 l 350 320 l 350 310 m 350 310 m 110 190 l 110 200 l 120 200 l 120 190 m 120 190 m 240 250 l 240 260 l 250 260 l 250 250 m 250 250 m 200 330 l 200 340 l 210 340 l 210 330 m 210 330 m 100 360 l 100 370 l 110 370 l 110 360 m 110 360 m 250 120 l 250 130 l 260 130 l 260 120 m 260 120 m 210 280 l 210 290 l 220 290 l 220 280 m 220 280 m 140 130 l 140 140 l 150 140 l 150 130 m 150 130 m 120 290 l 120 300 l 130 300 l 130 290 m 130 290 m 150 80 l 150 90 l 160 90 l 160 80 m 160 80 m 130 240 l 130 250 l 140 250 l 140 240 m 140 240 m 280 320 l 280 330 l 290 330 l 290 320 m 290 320 m 190 140 l 190 150 l 200 150 l 200 140 m 200 140 m 150 300 l 150 310 l 160 310 l 160 300 m 160 300 m 300 340 l 300 350 l 310 350 l 310 340 m 310 340 m 40 90 l 40 100 l 50 100 l 50 90 m 50 90 m 280 60 l 280 70 l 290 70 l 290 60 m 290 60 m 160 330 l 160 340 l 170 340 l 170 330 m 170 330 m 50 40 l 50 50 l 60 50 l 60 40 m 60 40 m 80 150 l 80 160 l 90 160 l 90 150 m 90 150 m 320 280 l 320 290 l 330 290 l 330 280 m 330 280 m 90 140 l 90 150 l 100 150 l 100 140 m 100 140 m 330 330 l 330 340 l 340 340 l 340 330 m 340 330 m 100 50 l 100 60 l 110 60 l 110 50 m 110 50 m 340 60 l 340 70 l 350 70 l 350 60 m 350 60 m 80 210 l 80 220 l 90 220 l 90 210 m 90 210 m 230 310 l 230 320 l 240 320 l 240 310 m 240 310 m 350 310 l 350 320 l 360 320 l 360 310 m 360 310 m 200 240 l 200 250 l 210 250 l 210 240 m 210 240 m 100 310 l 100 320 l 110 320 l 110 310 m 110 310 m 360 270 l 360 280 l 370 280 l 370 270 m 370 270 m 260 340 l 260 350 l 270 350 l 270 340 m 270 340 m 220 260 l 220 270 l 230 270 l 230 260 m 230 260 m 120 40 l 120 50 l 130 50 l 130 40 m 130 40 m 140 300 l 140 310 l 150 310 l 150 300 m 150 300 m 40 320 l 40 330 l 50 330 l 50 320 m 50 320 m 160 240 l 160 250 l 170 250 l 170 240 m 170 240 m 310 240 l 310 250 l 320 250 l 320 240 m 320 240 m 170 290 l 170 300 l 180 300 l 180 290 m 180 290 m 60 340 l 60 350 l 70 350 l 70 340 m 70 340 m 300 70 l 300 80 l 310 80 l 310 70 m 310 70 m 310 140 l 310 150 l 320 150 l 320 140 m 320 140 m 80 280 l 80 290 l 90 290 l 90 280 m 90 280 m 230 360 l 230 370 l 240 370 l 240 360 m 240 360 m 350 40 l 350 50 l 360 50 l 360 40 m 360 40 m 200 150 l 200 160 l 210 160 l 210 150 m 210 150 m 100 220 l 100 230 l 110 230 l 110 220 m 110 220 m 250 300 l 250 310 l 260 310 l 260 300 m 260 300 m 270 240 l 270 250 l 280 250 l 280 240 m 280 240 m 250 80 l 250 90 l 260 90 l 260 80 m 260 80 m 120 110 l 120 120 l 130 120 l 130 110 m 130 110 m 360 80 l 360 90 l 370 90 l 370 80 m 370 80 m 260 150 l 260 160 l 270 160 l 270 150 m 270 150 m 180 110 l 180 120 l 190 120 l 190 110 m 190 110 m 50 220 l 50 230 l 60 230 l 60 220 m 60 220 m 290 170 l 290 180 l 300 180 l 300 170 m 300 170 m 170 220 l 170 230 l 180 230 l 180 220 m 180 220 m 70 80 l 70 90 l 80 90 l 80 80 m 80 80 m 320 80 l 320 90 l 330 90 l 330 80 m 330 80 m 350 130 l 350 140 l 360 140 l 360 130 m 360 130 m 90 100 l 90 110 l 100 110 l 100 100 m 100 100 m 330 130 l 330 140 l 340 140 l 340 130 m 340 130 m 200 60 l 200 70 l 210 70 l 210 60 m 210 60 m 340 260 l 340 270 l 350 270 l 350 260 m 350 260 m 350 270 l 350 280 l 360 280 l 360 270 m 360 270 m 90 360 l 90 370 l 100 370 l 100 360 m 100 360 m 120 180 l 120 190 l 130 190 l 130 180 m 130 180 m 260 60 l 260 70 l 270 70 l 270 60 m 270 60 m 140 160 l 140 170 l 150 170 l 150 160 m 150 160 m 120 240 l 120 250 l 130 250 l 130 240 m 130 240 m 150 50 l 150 60 l 160 60 l 160 50 m 160 50 m 130 210 l 130 220 l 140 220 l 140 210 m 140 210 m 280 270 l 280 280 l 290 280 l 290 270 m 290 270 m 180 180 l 180 190 l 190 190 l 190 180 m 190 180 m 290 260 l 290 270 l 300 270 l 300 260 m 300 260 m 190 190 l 190 200 l 200 200 l 200 190 m 200 190 m 40 40 l 40 50 l 50 50 l 50 40 m 50 40 m 70 170 l 70 180 l 80 180 l 80 170 m 80 170 m 310 280 l 310 290 l 320 290 l 320 280 m 320 280 m 50 170 l 50 180 l 60 180 l 60 170 m 60 170 m 320 70 l 320 80 l 330 80 l 330 70 m 330 70 m 60 140 l 60 150 l 70 150 l 70 140 m 70 140 m 330 60 l 330 70 l 340 70 l 340 60 m 340 60 m 100 160 l 100 170 l 110 170 l 110 160 m 110 160 m 210 80 l 210 90 l 220 90 l 220 80 m 220 80 m 240 270 l 240 280 l 250 280 l 250 270 m 250 270 m 220 70 l 220 80 l 230 80 l 230 70 m 230 70 m 150 360 l 150 370 l 160 370 l 160 360 m 160 360 m 270 40 l 270 50 l 280 50 l 280 40 m 280 40 m 120 310 l 120 320 l 130 320 l 130 310 m 130 310 m 360 120 l 360 130 l 370 130 l 370 120 m 370 120 m 140 210 l 140 220 l 150 220 l 150 210 m 150 210 m 290 350 l 290 360 l 300 360 l 300 350 m 300 350 m 300 320 l 300 330 l 310 330 l 310 320 m 310 320 m 50 100 l 50 110 l 60 110 l 60 100 m 60 100 m 320 300 l 320 310 l 330 310 l 330 300 m 330 300 m 300 100 l 300 110 l 310 110 l 310 100 m 310 100 m 90 120 l 90 130 l 100 130 l 100 120 m 100 120 m 70 280 l 70 290 l 80 290 l 80 280 m 80 280 m 340 40 l 340 50 l 350 50 l 350 40 m 350 40 m 230 330 l 230 340 l 240 340 l 240 330 m 240 330 m 300 360 l 300 370 l 310 370 l 310 360 m 310 360 m 90 220 l 90 230 l 100 230 l 100 220 m 100 220 m 240 340 l 240 350 l 250 350 l 250 340 m 250 340 m 230 70 l 230 80 l 240 80 l 240 70 m 240 70 m 260 320 l 260 330 l 270 330 l 270 320 m 270 320 m 130 70 l 130 80 l 140 80 l 140 70 m 140 70 m 140 280 l 140 290 l 150 290 l 150 280 m 150 280 m 40 340 l 40 350 l 50 350 l 50 340 m 50 340 m 180 60 l 180 70 l 190 70 l 190 60 m 190 60 m 160 260 l 160 270 l 170 270 l 170 260 m 170 260 m 320 210 l 320 220 l 330 220 l 330 210 m 330 210 m 60 320 l 60 330 l 70 330 l 70 320 m 70 320 m 300 50 l 300 60 l 310 60 l 310 50 m 310 50 m 330 240 l 330 250 l 340 250 l 340 240 m 340 240 m 80 300 l 80 310 l 90 310 l 90 300 m 90 300 m 330 180 l 330 190 l 340 190 l 340 180 m 340 180 m 100 200 l 100 210 l 110 210 l 110 200 m 110 200 m 80 360 l 80 370 l 90 370 l 90 360 m 90 360 m 210 120 l 210 130 l 220 130 l 220 120 m 220 120 m 270 260 l 270 270 l 280 270 l 280 260 m 280 260 m 120 130 l 120 140 l 130 140 l 130 130 m 130 130 m 360 100 l 360 110 l 370 110 l 370 100 m 370 100 m 260 130 l 260 140 l 270 140 l 270 130 m 270 130 m 130 80 l 130 90 l 140 90 l 140 80 m 140 80 m 270 160 l 270 170 l 280 170 l 280 160 m 280 160 m 150 140 l 150 150 l 160 150 l 160 140 m 160 140 m 40 250 l 40 260 l 50 260 l 50 250 m 50 250 m 280 220 l 280 230 l 290 230 l 290 220 m 290 220 m 180 90 l 180 100 l 190 100 l 190 90 m 190 90 m 160 170 l 160 180 l 170 180 l 170 170 m 170 170 m 50 200 l 50 210 l 60 210 l 60 200 m 60 200 m 290 230 l 290 240 l 300 240 l 300 230 m 300 230 m 300 120 l 300 130 l 310 130 l 310 120 m 310 120 m 70 100 l 70 110 l 80 110 l 80 100 m 80 100 m 50 140 l 50 150 l 60 150 l 60 140 m 60 140 m 320 100 l 320 110 l 330 110 l 330 100 m 330 100 m 350 150 l 350 160 l 360 160 l 360 150 m 360 150 m 200 80 l 200 90 l 210 90 l 210 80 m 210 80 m 340 240 l 340 250 l 350 250 l 350 240 m 350 240 m 210 50 l 210 60 l 220 60 l 220 50 m 220 50 m 350 210 l 350 220 l 360 220 l 360 210 m 360 210 m 220 100 l 220 110 l 230 110 l 230 100 m 230 100 m 200 300 l 200 310 l 210 310 l 210 300 m 210 300 m 250 150 l 250 160 l 260 160 l 260 150 m 260 150 m 140 360 l 140 370 l 150 370 l 150 360 m 150 360 m 210 310 l 210 320 l 220 320 l 220 310 m 220 310 m 130 170 l 130 180 l 140 180 l 140 170 m 140 170 m 220 360 l 220 370 l 230 370 l 230 360 m 230 360 m 270 90 l 270 100 l 280 100 l 280 90 m 280 90 m 140 140 l 140 150 l 150 150 l 150 140 m 150 140 m 150 70 l 150 80 l 160 80 l 160 70 m 160 70 m 280 290 l 280 300 l 290 300 l 290 290 m 290 290 m 180 160 l 180 170 l 190 170 l 190 160 m 190 160 m 160 80 l 160 90 l 170 90 l 170 80 m 170 80 m 140 240 l 140 250 l 150 250 l 150 240 m 150 240 m 170 130 l 170 140 l 180 140 l 180 130 m 180 130 m 150 290 l 150 300 l 160 300 l 160 290 m 160 290 m 300 230 l 300 240 l 310 240 l 310 230 m 310 230 m 40 60 l 40 70 l 50 70 l 50 60 m 50 60 m 70 190 l 70 200 l 80 200 l 80 190 m 80 190 m 60 120 l 60 130 l 70 130 l 70 120 m 70 120 m 330 40 l 330 50 l 340 50 l 340 40 m 340 40 m 290 360 l 290 370 l 300 370 l 300 360 m 300 360 m 100 60 l 100 70 l 110 70 l 110 60 m 110 60 m 340 350 l 340 360 l 350 360 l 350 350 m 350 350 m 80 260 l 80 270 l 90 270 l 90 260 m 90 260 m 230 260 l 230 270 l 240 270 l 240 260 m 240 260 m 110 150 l 110 160 l 120 160 l 120 150 m 120 150 m 240 210 l 240 220 l 250 220 l 250 210 m 250 210 m 200 210 l 200 220 l 210 220 l 210 210 m 210 210 m 210 320 l 210 330 l 220 330 l 220 320 m 220 320 m 360 240 l 360 250 l 370 250 l 370 240 m 370 240 m 220 310 l 220 320 l 230 320 l 230 310 m 230 310 m 270 60 l 270 70 l 280 70 l 280 60 m 280 60 m 120 330 l 120 340 l 130 340 l 130 330 m 130 330 m 180 270 l 180 280 l 190 280 l 190 270 m 190 270 m 190 260 l 190 270 l 200 270 l 200 260 m 200 260 m 170 60 l 170 70 l 180 70 l 180 60 m 180 60 m 300 300 l 300 310 l 310 310 l 310 300 m 310 300 m 280 100 l 280 110 l 290 110 l 290 100 m 290 100 m 160 290 l 160 300 l 170 300 l 170 290 m 170 290 m 310 230 l 310 240 l 320 240 l 320 230 m 320 230 m 170 320 l 170 330 l 180 330 l 180 320 m 180 320 m 320 240 l 320 250 l 330 250 l 330 240 m 330 240 m 60 70 l 60 80 l 70 80 l 70 70 m 70 70 m 300 80 l 300 90 l 310 90 l 310 80 m 310 80 m 330 290 l 330 300 l 340 300 l 340 290 m 340 290 m 70 300 l 70 310 l 80 310 l 80 300 m 80 300 m 100 90 l 100 100 l 110 100 l 110 90 m 110 90 m 340 100 l 340 110 l 350 110 l 350 100 m 350 100 m 80 330 l 80 340 l 90 340 l 90 330 m 90 330 m 70 360 l 70 370 l 80 370 l 80 360 m 80 360 m 100 350 l 100 360 l 110 360 l 110 350 m 110 350 m 250 330 l 250 340 l 260 340 l 260 330 m 260 330 m 240 100 l 240 110 l 250 110 l 250 100 m 250 100 m 220 220 l 220 230 l 230 230 l 230 220 m 230 220 m 270 310 l 270 320 l 280 320 l 280 310 m 280 310 m 360 50 l 360 60 l 370 60 l 370 50 m 370 50 m 180 340 l 180 350 l 190 350 l 190 340 m 190 340 m 140 100 l 140 110 l 150 110 l 150 100 m 150 100 m 280 170 l 280 180 l 290 180 l 290 170 m 290 170 m 160 200 l 160 210 l 170 210 l 170 200 m 170 200 m 190 90 l 190 100 l 200 100 l 200 90 m 200 90 m 170 250 l 170 260 l 180 260 l 180 250 m 180 250 m 320 230 l 320 240 l 330 240 l 330 230 m 330 230 m 60 300 l 60 310 l 70 310 l 70 300 m 70 300 m 300 190 l 300 200 l 310 200 l 310 190 m 310 190 m 70 70 l 70 80 l 80 80 l 80 70 m 80 70 m 340 130 l 340 140 l 350 140 l 350 130 m 350 130 m 80 80 l 80 90 l 90 90 l 90 80 m 90 80 m 330 160 l 330 170 l 340 170 l 340 160 m 340 160 m 100 260 l 100 270 l 110 270 l 110 260 m 110 260 m 210 180 l 210 190 l 220 190 l 220 180 m 220 180 m 110 270 l 110 280 l 120 280 l 120 270 m 120 270 m 260 250 l 260 260 l 270 260 l 270 250 m 270 250 m 240 170 l 240 180 l 250 180 l 250 170 m 250 170 m 130 360 l 130 370 l 140 370 l 140 360 m 140 360 m 250 40 l 250 50 l 260 50 l 260 40 m 260 40 m 210 360 l 210 370 l 220 370 l 220 360 m 220 360 m 360 280 l 360 290 l 370 290 l 370 280 m 370 280 m 260 190 l 260 200 l 270 200 l 270 190 m 270 190 m 130 140 l 130 150 l 140 150 l 140 140 m 140 140 m 270 180 l 270 190 l 280 190 l 280 180 m 280 180 m 140 50 l 140 60 l 150 60 l 150 50 m 150 50 m 280 240 l 280 250 l 290 250 l 290 240 m 290 240 m 160 190 l 160 200 l 170 200 l 170 190 m 170 190 m 290 210 l 290 220 l 300 220 l 300 210 m 300 210 m 60 250 l 60 260 l 70 260 l 70 250 m 70 250 m 300 260 l 300 270 l 310 270 l 310 260 m 310 260 m 40 170 l 40 180 l 50 180 l 50 170 m 50 170 m 70 120 l 70 130 l 80 130 l 80 120 m 80 120 m 80 70 l 80 80 l 90 80 l 90 70 m 90 70 m 320 40 l 320 50 l 330 50 l 330 40 m 330 40 m 200 100 l 200 110 l 210 110 l 210 100 m 210 100 m 230 230 l 230 240 l 240 240 l 240 230 m 240 230 m 210 110 l 210 120 l 220 120 l 220 110 m 220 110 m 350 230 l 350 240 l 360 240 l 360 230 m 360 230 m 220 80 l 220 90 l 230 90 l 230 80 m 230 80 m 200 320 l 200 330 l 210 330 l 210 320 m 210 320 m 360 350 l 360 360 l 370 360 l 370 350 m 370 350 m 260 100 l 260 110 l 270 110 l 270 100 m 270 100 m 220 340 l 220 350 l 230 350 l 230 340 m 230 340 m 270 110 l 270 120 l 280 120 l 280 110 m 280 110 m 140 120 l 140 130 l 150 130 l 150 120 m 150 120 m 150 90 l 150 100 l 160 100 l 160 90 m 160 90 m 280 310 l 280 320 l 290 320 l 290 310 m 290 310 m 160 100 l 160 110 l 170 110 l 170 100 m 170 100 m 140 220 l 140 230 l 150 230 l 150 220 m 150 220 m 300 210 l 300 220 l 310 220 l 310 210 m 310 210 m 40 80 l 40 90 l 50 90 l 50 80 m 50 80 m 160 320 l 160 330 l 170 330 l 170 320 m 170 320 m 310 320 l 310 330 l 320 330 l 320 320 m 320 320 m 320 350 l 320 360 l 330 360 l 330 350 m 330 350 m 60 100 l 60 110 l 70 110 l 70 100 m 70 100 m 100 40 l 100 50 l 110 50 l 110 40 m 110 40 m 80 200 l 80 210 l 90 210 l 90 200 m 90 200 m 230 280 l 230 290 l 240 290 l 240 280 m 240 280 m 60 360 l 60 370 l 70 370 l 70 360 m 70 360 m 100 300 l 100 310 l 110 310 l 110 300 m 110 300 m 250 220 l 250 230 l 260 230 l 260 220 m 260 220 m 360 260 l 360 270 l 370 270 l 370 260 m 370 260 m 220 290 l 220 300 l 230 300 l 230 290 m 230 290 m 270 320 l 270 330 l 280 330 l 280 320 m 280 320 m 180 250 l 180 260 l 190 260 l 190 250 m 190 250 m 140 330 l 140 340 l 150 340 l 150 330 m 150 330 m 150 200 l 150 210 l 160 210 l 160 200 m 160 200 m 300 280 l 300 290 l 310 290 l 310 280 m 310 280 m 40 310 l 40 320 l 50 320 l 50 310 m 50 310 m 160 310 l 160 320 l 170 320 l 170 310 m 170 310 m 310 250 l 310 260 l 320 260 l 320 250 m 320 250 m 50 300 l 50 310 l 60 310 l 60 300 m 60 300 m 170 300 l 170 310 l 180 310 l 180 300 m 180 300 m 300 60 l 300 70 l 310 70 l 310 60 m 310 60 m 330 270 l 330 280 l 340 280 l 340 270 m 340 270 m 70 320 l 70 330 l 80 330 l 80 320 m 80 320 m 310 150 l 310 160 l 320 160 l 320 150 m 320 150 m 340 80 l 340 90 l 350 90 l 350 80 m 350 80 m 240 300 l 240 310 l 250 310 l 250 300 m 250 300 m 200 140 l 200 150 l 210 150 l 210 140 m 210 140 m 100 330 l 100 340 l 110 340 l 110 330 m 110 330 m 230 110 l 230 120 l 240 120 l 240 110 m 240 110 m 210 150 l 210 160 l 220 160 l 220 150 m 220 150 m 120 360 l 120 370 l 130 370 l 130 360 m 130 360 m 260 200 l 260 210 l 270 210 l 270 200 m 270 200 m 240 40 l 240 50 l 250 50 l 250 40 m 250 40 m 220 200 l 220 210 l 230 210 l 230 200 m 230 200 m 250 90 l 250 100 l 260 100 l 260 90 m 260 90 m 120 100 l 120 110 l 130 110 l 130 100 m 130 100 m 360 70 l 360 80 l 370 80 l 370 70 m 370 70 m 260 140 l 260 150 l 270 150 l 270 140 m 270 140 m 140 80 l 140 90 l 150 90 l 150 80 m 150 80 m 190 290 l 190 300 l 200 300 l 200 290 m 200 290 m 40 220 l 40 230 l 50 230 l 50 220 m 50 220 m 280 190 l 280 200 l 290 200 l 290 190 m 290 190 m 180 100 l 180 110 l 190 110 l 190 100 m 190 100 m 190 110 l 190 120 l 200 120 l 200 110 m 200 110 m 170 230 l 170 240 l 180 240 l 180 230 m 180 230 m 60 280 l 60 290 l 70 290 l 70 280 m 70 280 m 300 170 l 300 180 l 310 180 l 310 170 m 310 170 m 40 120 l 40 130 l 50 130 l 50 120 m 50 120 m 310 40 l 310 50 l 320 50 l 320 40 m 320 40 m 340 190 l 340 200 l 350 200 l 350 190 m 350 190 m 80 100 l 80 110 l 90 110 l 90 100 m 90 100 m 330 140 l 330 150 l 340 150 l 340 140 m 340 140 m 100 240 l 100 250 l 110 250 l 110 240 m 110 240 m 230 160 l 230 170 l 240 170 l 240 160 m 240 160 m 110 210 l 110 220 l 120 220 l 120 210 m 120 210 m 360 300 l 360 310 l 370 310 l 370 300 m 370 300 m 130 220 l 130 230 l 140 230 l 140 220 m 140 220 m 50 240 l 50 250 l 60 250 l 60 240 m 60 240 m 190 160 l 190 170 l 200 170 l 200 160 m 200 160 m 60 230 l 60 240 l 70 240 l 70 230 m 70 230 m 300 240 l 300 250 l 310 250 l 310 240 m 310 240 m 50 180 l 50 190 l 60 190 l 60 180 m 60 180 m 80 170 l 80 180 l 90 180 l 90 170 m 90 170 m 320 60 l 320 70 l 330 70 l 330 60 m 330 60 m 60 170 l 60 180 l 70 180 l 70 170 m 70 170 m 90 40 l 90 50 l 100 50 l 100 40 m 100 40 m 330 70 l 330 80 l 340 80 l 340 70 m 340 70 m 50 360 l 50 370 l 60 370 l 60 360 m 60 360 m 340 280 l 340 290 l 350 290 l 350 280 m 350 280 m 210 90 l 210 100 l 220 100 l 220 90 m 220 90 m 110 180 l 110 190 l 120 190 l 120 180 m 120 180 m 240 260 l 240 270 l 250 270 l 250 260 m 250 260 m 220 60 l 220 70 l 230 70 l 230 60 m 230 60 m 200 340 l 200 350 l 210 350 l 210 340 m 210 340 m 210 350 l 210 360 l 220 360 l 220 350 m 220 350 m 220 320 l 220 330 l 230 330 l 230 320 m 230 320 m 270 50 l 270 60 l 280 60 l 280 50 m 280 50 m 120 300 l 120 310 l 130 310 l 130 300 m 130 300 m 180 200 l 180 210 l 190 210 l 190 200 m 190 200 m 290 280 l 290 290 l 300 290 l 300 280 m 300 280 m 190 250 l 190 260 l 200 260 l 200 250 m 200 250 m 170 90 l 170 100 l 180 100 l 180 90 m 180 90 m 40 100 l 40 110 l 50 110 l 50 100 m 50 100 m 280 70 l 280 80 l 290 80 l 290 70 m 290 70 m 310 340 l 310 350 l 320 350 l 320 340 m 320 340 m 320 290 l 320 300 l 330 300 l 330 290 m 330 290 m 60 80 l 60 90 l 70 90 l 70 80 m 70 80 m 100 100 l 100 110 l 110 110 l 110 100 m 110 100 m 340 70 l 340 80 l 350 80 l 350 70 m 350 70 m 80 220 l 80 230 l 90 230 l 90 220 m 90 220 m 230 300 l 230 310 l 240 310 l 240 300 m 240 300 m 200 250 l 200 260 l 210 260 l 210 250 m 210 250 m 100 280 l 100 290 l 110 290 l 110 280 m 110 280 m 250 200 l 250 210 l 260 210 l 260 200 m 260 200 m 270 360 l 270 370 l 280 370 l 280 360 m 280 360 m 230 40 l 230 50 l 240 50 l 240 40 m 240 40 m 210 200 l 210 210 l 220 210 l 220 200 m 220 200 m 220 270 l 220 280 l 230 280 l 230 270 m 230 270 m 120 50 l 120 60 l 130 60 l 130 50 m 130 50 m 190 220 l 190 230 l 200 230 l 200 220 m 200 220 m 40 330 l 40 340 l 50 340 l 50 330 m 50 330 m 280 140 l 280 150 l 290 150 l 290 140 m 290 140 m 310 270 l 310 280 l 320 280 l 320 270 m 320 270 m 320 200 l 320 210 l 330 210 l 330 200 m 330 200 m 300 40 l 300 50 l 310 50 l 310 40 m 310 40 m 70 340 l 70 350 l 80 350 l 80 340 m 80 340 m 330 190 l 330 200 l 340 200 l 340 190 m 340 190 m 200 160 l 200 170 l 210 170 l 210 160 m 210 160 m 250 290 l 250 300 l 260 300 l 260 290 m 260 290 m 230 130 l 230 140 l 240 140 l 240 130 m 240 130 m 210 130 l 210 140 l 220 140 l 220 130 m 220 130 m 240 60 l 240 70 l 250 70 l 250 60 m 250 60 m 220 180 l 220 190 l 230 190 l 230 180 m 230 180 m 270 270 l 270 280 l 280 280 l 280 270 m 280 270 m 250 70 l 250 80 l 260 80 l 260 70 m 260 70 m 360 90 l 360 100 l 370 100 l 370 90 m 370 90 m 130 90 l 130 100 l 140 100 l 140 90 m 140 90 m 270 170 l 270 180 l 280 180 l 280 170 m 280 170 m 140 60 l 140 70 l 150 70 l 150 60 m 150 60 m 190 310 l 190 320 l 200 320 l 200 310 m 200 310 m 150 150 l 150 160 l 160 160 l 160 150 m 160 150 m 40 240 l 40 250 l 50 250 l 50 240 m 50 240 m 280 210 l 280 220 l 290 220 l 290 210 m 290 210 m 50 210 l 50 220 l 60 220 l 60 210 m 60 210 m 290 160 l 290 170 l 300 170 l 300 160 m 300 160 m 190 50 l 190 60 l 200 60 l 200 50 m 200 50 m 60 260 l 60 270 l 70 270 l 70 260 m 70 260 m 300 150 l 300 160 l 310 160 l 310 150 m 310 150 m 50 150 l 50 160 l 60 160 l 60 150 m 60 150 m 340 170 l 340 180 l 350 180 l 350 170 m 350 170 m 80 40 l 80 50 l 90 50 l 90 40 m 90 40 m 40 360 l 40 370 l 50 370 l 50 360 m 50 360 m 350 120 l 350 130 l 360 130 l 360 120 m 360 120 m 330 120 l 330 130 l 340 130 l 340 120 m 340 120 m 100 140 l 100 150 l 110 150 l 110 140 m 110 140 m 340 270 l 340 280 l 350 280 l 350 270 m 350 270 m 230 180 l 230 190 l 240 190 l 240 180 m 240 180 m 110 230 l 110 240 l 120 240 l 120 230 m 120 230 m 350 260 l 350 270 l 360 270 l 360 260 m 360 260 m 220 130 l 220 140 l 230 140 l 230 130 m 230 130 m 250 160 l 250 170 l 260 170 l 260 160 m 260 160 m 120 190 l 120 200 l 130 200 l 130 190 m 130 190 m 270 140 l 270 150 l 280 150 l 280 140 m 280 140 m 140 170 l 140 180 l 150 180 l 150 170 m 150 170 m 130 200 l 130 210 l 140 210 l 140 200 m 140 200 m 280 280 l 280 290 l 290 290 l 290 280 m 290 280 m 170 140 l 170 150 l 180 150 l 180 140 m 180 140 m 60 210 l 60 220 l 70 220 l 70 210 m 70 210 m 40 50 l 40 60 l 50 60 l 50 50 m 50 50 m 50 160 l 50 170 l 60 170 l 60 160 m 60 160 m 80 190 l 80 200 l 90 200 l 90 190 m 90 190 m 320 320 l 320 330 l 330 330 l 330 320 m 330 320 m 60 150 l 60 160 l 70 160 l 70 150 m 70 150 m 90 180 l 90 190 l 100 190 l 100 180 m 100 180 m 80 250 l 80 260 l 90 260 l 90 250 m 90 250 m 110 120 l 110 130 l 120 130 l 120 120 m 120 120 m 240 200 l 240 210 l 250 210 l 250 200 m 250 200 m 200 200 l 200 210 l 210 210 l 210 200 m 210 200 m 250 250 l 250 260 l 260 260 l 260 250 m 260 250 m 360 230 l 360 240 l 370 240 l 370 230 m 370 230 m 220 300 l 220 310 l 230 310 l 230 300 m 230 300 m 270 70 l 270 80 l 280 80 l 280 70 m 280 70 m 180 260 l 180 270 l 190 270 l 190 260 m 190 260 m 190 270 l 190 280 l 200 280 l 200 270 m 200 270 m 150 350 l 150 360 l 160 360 l 160 350 m 160 350 m 40 280 l 40 290 l 50 290 l 50 280 m 50 280 m 320 310 l 320 320 l 330 320 l 330 310 m 330 310 m 60 60 l 60 70 l 70 70 l 70 60 m 70 60 m 100 80 l 100 90 l 110 90 l 110 80 m 110 80 m 80 320 l 80 330 l 90 330 l 90 320 m 90 320 m 90 210 l 90 220 l 100 220 l 100 210 m 100 210 m 240 350 l 240 360 l 250 360 l 250 350 m 250 350 m 100 340 l 100 350 l 110 350 l 110 340 m 110 340 m 210 260 l 210 270 l 220 270 l 220 260 m 220 260 m 260 330 l 260 340 l 270 340 l 270 330 m 270 330 m 270 280 l 270 290 l 280 290 l 280 280 m 280 280 m 120 70 l 120 80 l 130 80 l 130 70 m 130 70 m 360 40 l 360 50 l 370 50 l 370 40 m 370 40 m 130 60 l 130 70 l 140 70 l 140 60 m 140 60 m 140 290 l 140 300 l 150 300 l 150 290 m 150 290 m 190 320 l 190 330 l 200 330 l 200 320 m 200 320 m 150 240 l 150 250 l 160 250 l 160 240 m 160 240 m 40 350 l 40 360 l 50 360 l 50 350 m 50 350 m 290 130 l 290 140 l 300 140 l 300 130 m 300 130 m 170 260 l 170 270 l 180 270 l 180 260 m 180 260 m 320 220 l 320 230 l 330 230 l 330 220 m 330 220 m 60 330 l 60 340 l 70 340 l 70 330 m 70 330 m 70 40 l 70 50 l 80 50 l 80 40 m 80 40 m 350 170 l 350 180 l 360 180 l 360 170 m 360 170 m 90 300 l 90 310 l 100 310 l 100 300 m 100 300 m 330 170 l 330 180 l 340 180 l 340 170 m 340 170 m 340 220 l 340 230 l 350 230 l 350 220 m 350 220 m 230 150 l 230 160 l 240 160 l 240 150 m 240 150 m 110 240 l 110 250 l 120 250 l 120 240 m 120 240 m 260 240 l 260 250 l 270 250 l 270 240 m 270 240 m 240 160 l 240 170 l 250 170 l 250 160 m 250 160 m 270 210 l 270 220 l 280 220 l 280 210 m 280 210 m 260 180 l 260 190 l 270 190 l 270 180 m 270 180 m 270 190 l 270 200 l 280 200 l 280 190 m 280 190 m 140 40 l 140 50 l 150 50 l 150 40 m 150 40 m 120 200 l 120 210 l 130 210 l 130 200 m 130 200 m 150 170 l 150 180 l 160 180 l 160 170 m 160 170 m 160 180 l 160 190 l 170 190 l 170 180 m 170 180 m 50 270 l 50 280 l 60 280 l 60 270 m 60 270 m 60 240 l 60 250 l 70 250 l 70 240 m 70 240 m 300 130 l 300 140 l 310 140 l 310 130 m 310 130 m 40 160 l 40 170 l 50 170 l 50 160 m 50 160 m 70 130 l 70 140 l 80 140 l 80 130 m 80 130 m 80 60 l 80 70 l 90 70 l 90 60 m 90 60 m 60 180 l 60 190 l 70 190 l 70 180 m 70 180 m 350 140 l 350 150 l 360 150 l 360 140 m 360 140 m 330 100 l 330 110 l 340 110 l 340 100 m 340 100 m 200 90 l 200 100 l 210 100 l 210 90 m 210 90 m 100 120 l 100 130 l 110 130 l 110 120 m 110 120 m 340 250 l 340 260 l 350 260 l 350 250 m 350 250 m 250 360 l 250 370 l 260 370 l 260 360 m 260 360 m 240 150 l 240 160 l 250 160 l 250 150 m 250 150 m 330 360 l 330 370 l 340 370 l 340 360 m 340 360 m 250 140 l 250 150 l 260 150 l 260 140 m 260 140 m 210 300 l 210 310 l 220 310 l 220 300 m 220 300 m 130 160 l 130 170 l 140 170 l 140 160 m 140 160 m 270 80 l 270 90 l 280 90 l 280 80 m 280 80 m 130 260 l 130 270 l 140 270 l 140 260 m 140 260 m 280 300 l 280 310 l 290 310 l 290 300 m 290 300 m 180 170 l 180 180 l 190 180 l 190 170 m 190 170 m 160 90 l 160 100 l 170 100 l 170 90 m 170 90 m 140 250 l 140 260 l 150 260 l 150 250 m 150 250 m 190 120 l 190 130 l 200 130 l 200 120 m 200 120 m 170 120 l 170 130 l 180 130 l 180 120 m 180 120 m 150 280 l 150 290 l 160 290 l 160 280 m 160 280 m 300 200 l 300 210 l 310 210 l 310 200 m 310 200 m 40 70 l 40 80 l 50 80 l 50 70 m 50 70 m 280 40 l 280 50 l 290 50 l 290 40 m 290 40 m 70 180 l 70 190 l 80 190 l 80 180 m 80 180 m 90 160 l 90 170 l 100 170 l 100 160 m 100 160 m 330 350 l 330 360 l 340 360 l 340 350 m 340 350 m 100 70 l 100 80 l 110 80 l 110 70 m 110 70 m 340 320 l 340 330 l 350 330 l 350 320 m 350 320 m 230 290 l 230 300 l 240 300 l 240 290 m 240 290 m 240 220 l 240 230 l 250 230 l 250 220 m 250 220 m 210 230 l 210 240 l 220 240 l 220 230 m 220 230 m 360 250 l 360 260 l 370 260 l 370 250 m 370 250 m 220 280 l 220 290 l 230 290 l 230 280 m 230 280 m 270 330 l 270 340 l 280 340 l 280 330 m 280 330 m 120 340 l 120 350 l 130 350 l 130 340 m 130 340 m 360 150 l 360 160 l 370 160 l 370 150 m 370 150 m 290 320 l 290 330 l 300 330 l 300 320 m 300 320 m 190 210 l 190 220 l 200 220 l 200 210 m 200 210 m 40 300 l 40 310 l 50 310 l 50 300 m 50 300 m 320 250 l 320 260 l 330 260 l 330 250 m 330 250 m 60 40 l 60 50 l 70 50 l 70 40 m 70 40 m 300 90 l 300 100 l 310 100 l 310 90 m 310 90 m 330 280 l 330 290 l 340 290 l 340 280 m 340 280 m 70 330 l 70 340 l 80 340 l 80 330 m 80 330 m 80 340 l 80 350 l 90 350 l 90 340 m 90 340
是的 就在明晚